You know, one of the first things I did when we were getting the place of saying we're
going to merge was I took him out for dinner.
And at the end of dinner, I said, oh, your wife's going to join us.
We're here.
Let's buy a dinner for her, too, because you keep the sound man happy.
They can make you look good or...
So, first series and what is in a name.
You do know names matter.
My wife and I are eliminating 95% of our possessions.
We're trying to give stuff to our kids.
Two of them were able to give stuff to because they have a home.
One has a home, but it's in Japan.
It's really hard to ship stuff over there.
And so we talked our son into storing our daughter's stuff.
So, not in our basement anymore.
But one of the things we gave to Josiah, our oldest, was his baby book.
And I didn't realize that he was going to read it really quick.
And he made lots of comments about it.
But the first comment he made was what his mother and then I wrote under the section about why we named him Josiah.
Names matter.
I mean, not a biblical.
Adam was called after a word for ground.
Because God took ground, formed it, breathed into it, and humans existed.
Now, you know the old joke about the scientists and God competing and the scientists saying, I can create life too.
And God saying, okay, well, let me show you.
And he took the ground and breathed into it.
And there was man.
And the scientists picked up the ground.
And God said, no, no, no.
Go get your own ground.
Eve was called life.
And his name is life.
Because she was the mother of all human life.
It goes back to Eve.
Jacob actually had two names.
He was called surplanter.
Because early in the story of one of our patriarchs, one of our fathers in the face, he was a surplanter.
He stole his brother's birthright.
He stole his tricks to get his brother's blessing.
And when God finally took him the place of moving him into living out his call in the greater purposes of God, he wrestled with God all night.
And then he renamed him Israel, which means wrestled with God.
No, he's not.
Daniel, who struggled over living in a foreign nation where they required him to eat things that the law didn't allow him to eat.
And he chose not to.
And he thought he would have to suffer because he was choosing not to follow what Nebuchadnezzar was saying.
He said, well, let's do a test here.
You guys eat what you eat, we'll eat what we eat, and let's see what happens.
And then, he turned out well.
And, you know, his name means God is judge.
The Scriptures are full of names, moderns.
Jesus even points out to Peter and makes a theological statement about Peter being rocked.
In fact, what is Jesus?
God, yeah, yeah.
That God chose the name of his son who would save the whole world.
In fact, you can argue save the universe because his salvation was not just us, but it was all of creation, which was marred by sin.
Jesus, God, save.
I often like to point out that my mother wisely called me not here, which means gift of God.
And we see this in so many places.
We see it in denominations.
If we were Lutheran, it would be because we...
You can talk to me.
It's okay.
What's that?
Yeah, we're a loser.
We saw all of it's mutual remarked.
Just the carrying.
It's a form of governance.
You know, I thought these dudes were talked back to me.
I thought we were getting a younger congregation with the legion dialogue.
That's his monologue.
I'm sorry.
I missed something.
Okay.
Let's try it again.
Pentecostal holiness.
There's all Pentecostal, the Holy Spirit fell out.
And this is doctrinally.
It's doctrinally driven.
I love this one.
Salvation Army.
I love that name.
I really do.
It says a lot about what our goal and purposes are as the church.
Let's get a little more personal here.
Brethren.
Yeah, it's the community of God.
We really value the community of the brethren, the people.
Independence.
Okay.
So, Kansas Community Church.
You know, you can argue that we tried to say,
Okay, Kansas Church, there was a lot of momentum.
There was a great room.
We let's take that.
But Grace Community, we want to add the word community to it.
It's kind of a mixture together.
But for me, there was a much deeper theological reason.
And I think it was true for you as well.
And so, we want to look at the verse, at the passage.
And I know I've listened to the last, well,
all but one of the sermons that were given during this season of Your Part Matters.
And it was mentioned often that this word, Kansas,
it comes from Ephesians 2, verse 10.
But I'd like to unpack it with you this morning, if I can.
And let me start by saying that specific verse
is the link between the first half of Ephesians 2
and the second half of Ephesians 2.
The first half of Ephesians 2 really addresses our individual salvation.
We sang about, I'm a child of God.
By the way, at some point, I'm going to ask you to pop those slides up for the song,
the second Song we did of, I'm a child of God,
like a walk through the waters, you know, that God held back,
and all that kind of stuff.
Ephesians 2, verse 10, is the climax of that passage.
And I'll show it to you in the text.
But it's also the foundation for the rest of chapter 2,
which is also talking about salvation,
but it's not talking about individual salvation.
It's all about a collective salvation.
God saves the person, He also saves the people.
God redeems a person.
He also redeems a people.
But God creates a person in Him, but He also creates a people in Him.
And this piece that we have of Ephesians chapter 2,
and the verse in the middle, the one that we've chosen our name from,
is the climax of the first and the foundation of the second.
So what I'd like to do is walk you through the five words that are in the beginning of that.
We're going to take three weeks to do it.
And today, my assignment is the first five words.
For we are His canvas.
Of His four concepts.
And since the word canvas is in our name,
I'm going to start there, and then I'll back up and I'll walk through the words.
The canvas means, it comes from the word poema.
It literally means work, or product.
It's God's, we are God's product.
And some translations put it as, we are His workmanship.
And it's used in Koine Greek work and product in several places,
but it only shows up twice in the whole New Testament.
And I'm going to reference both of those where they show up.
But in both cases, the first one you can see it so clearly,
the second one you can see it as well.
Those are by Paul.
It references some theological work by Karl Barth.
It said it's not just a product, but it's not just a work,
but it carries a connotation of a work of art.
That God has written a poem, or He's painted a canvas.
And it's going to be kind of fun,
because the canvas is kind of like the kingdom of God.
It is here.
It's done.
God has finished His masterpiece, and it's unbelievable.
And yet the kingdom's coming.
And so He's still painted.
He's still, He's still designed.
It's done.
But He's still designed.
He's still painted.
It's a work.
It's interesting that when Paul puts it in there,
this word for work, polemah,
he puts it, he uses another word for work,
and he uses it twice.
He bookends it on either side of Ephesians 2,
and it's the word that we most often see in the Bible for a work.
Because he says in 2, verse 8 and 9,
and you can probably quote it.
Or at least some of you can.
If you went through VBS, you were probably made to quote this verse.
If you've been through Evangelism Training 101,
you're probably made to memorize this verse.
Well, we are saved by grace through faith,
not of yourselves,
not of work,
plus what?
Anyone can boast.
What is fascinating to me is that every Evangelism Training course I've talked
and every VBS I've been part of,
they don't end there,
and they never finish the rest of the part.
We can quote the first two.
We're getting around to the third one.
But in this third one,
Paul is pulling us of the 8 and 9,
where good works cannot save you.
God is perfect,
and we can never arrive at perfection on our own.
We can never do enough.
It requires this incredible act of forgiveness from God.
Someone has said that in a sense,
we have not just broken God's law,
but we broke God's heart.
And that if I ran over your daughter with a car
because I was texting or drinking,
and I would go to a court,
and I'd be found guilty,
and I'd serve my sentence,
and when I was done with my sentence,
I'd pay my fines,
and when I came out of that context,
as far as the law is concerned,
I'm good to go.
But as far as Mom's concerned,
I'm only good to go when she can give
a gracious,
unowned,
ask of forgiveness.
that our good works
can never leave us.
We can never be kidding us.
It's by getting,
and we don't even get that
by doing good things
to show God we're worthy of this grace,
because then it's not grace.
It's by faith.
We receive it.
But then he bookends this good work,
because God cannot imagine anyone ever thinking
that we can make it to God
by following the law.
He tried.
And he realized how sweet the law it was.
And yet on the flip side,
Paul can not imagine a salvation
that is not resulting in good works.
But we are his,
his work is the peace canvas,
creating Christ Jesus,
unto good works,
and then let me reiterate it,
Paul says.
Because God is actually praying
ahead of time for you.
Now, I'm not going to do that passage.
We'll leave it to Ryan.
I'm not going to take your material.
But,
but it's,
it's critical that Paul takes this ergon,
this word works,
and in between it,
he uses this unique word
that only shows up twice
in the entire New Testament.
And we can translate it.
Canvas.
This word works.
So the first one,
it's a different canvas
than this one.
But it's the same person
making the canvas.
It's in Romans 1.20.
The first thing is
a different canvas,
but both canvases
have the exact same endgame,
the exact same purpose.
In the Romans 1.20,
the canvas is his creation.
His original creation.
I've just spent the last
six weeks in Yellowstone.
the most beautiful place
in the world.
There's no place like it.
The wilderness thing.
We saw four grizzly builders.
Four different counties.
One of them was
swimming in Lake Yellowstone.
We pulled over a car
50 feet off the beach.
And he'd swing for a while
and he'd stop
and he'd stand up
and he'd look at us.
And then he'd swing a little farther
and meanwhile
all these other cars came in
and so the road
was full of cars.
This poor bear
was trying to get out
into the water.
We all had him trapped in.
But unbelievable.
Almost every morning,
almost every evening
you would hear
Elf Bugle.
And just
geothermal.
I've done a short picture
and I thought my,
I shouldn't do it
the first Sunday
my wife's here
because she wouldn't
be happy with me.
There's a picture of her
in fact she said to me
she was hoping
to sit in the bathroom
and when she stood back there
she couldn't find a seat
so she had to come up front.
I mentioned Providence
but that didn't help either.
So it's a picture
of her sitting in this pool
that's about the size
of our stage
and it's the outflow
from a natural thought place
about 104 degrees.
And you get in
it's like the perfect
thought temperature.
And you're looking down
over this river
that flows through
a meandering meadow
that's nestled
underneath these
snow-capped mountains
or these snow-dusted mountains.
And sitting there
I was hearing Elf Bugle
and I mean
my only word was
God bless you.
I mean he just did
this amazing
canvas in creation.
But if you read
Romans 1.20
there's a purpose
for this canvas
in creation.
It's not just the purpose
of creating this artwork
but he says
very clearly
that it shows
God's invisible
quality.
And then he names
two of them
in the original
canvas that God does.
It's the original creation.
His eternal power
and he's going to make it.
And he's going to say
you know people
are without excuse
because how can you
walk in the
beauty of his canvas
and not say
God
look in the sky
look at the ocean
you've changed it.
Go up here
20 minutes
and get on the 18th
and go through the
rollercoaster
and it's a strange
God.
But theologians
have told us
for a long time
his natural revelation
only shows us
God the creator.
So is his
incredible power
and his divine nature
that he is
all powerful
and that he is
omniscient
and he's the
omnibus of
all forms.
But to know
the redeemer God
is special revelation.
And so here
in our presence
when we have been
choosing the name
canvas
that Paul used
for this
second
new creation
of day
it's purpose
which is so
God's invisible qualities
as a deed.
It's the truth
of Jesus Christ
the bride
of God's
Son
is divine
to the strength.
God's ego.
Canvas one
creation
Canvas two
new creation
his son's brother.
That's why we took
the name.
The first is
God's creator
the second is
God's redeemer
and you could argue
actually that
the
medicines
of the whole
Bible
fall into
or the
medicine
of the whole
Bible
falls into
those two
themes
creator
redeemer.
The whole
Bible
and by the way
we get to
play into those
themes
but our two
parts are
fall and
faith.
Faithless
faithful.
And I'm
not going to
today
but you could
argue
there's
actually
a third
canvas
coming
and that's
not about
God the
creator
or God
the redeemer
but about
God the
Christ
remember
and there
will be a new
heaven and a
new earth
and God's
people will be
with him
and you will
not need a
son because
his life will
be such in our
presence that we
will know.
In fact when we're
there we will
know as fully as
we are known.
I don't know
about you but I
do not know me as
well as God
means me and I
will know not
just me but all
as fully as God
means me.
That's a third
canvas I look
forward to.
Okay that's the
bulk of my
message.
I do want to
unpack the other
four words.
First one
four and the
four we are
his canvas.
Four.
Verse 10
by the simple
word four
it indicates
that verse
10 is the
penultimate.
It's the
consequence.
why of verse
8 and 9.
That's why I'm
personally bothered
that in Evangelism
101 we get
people to
memorize 8 and
9 and we
never get around
to the why of
the 8 and
the 9.
I mean it's
really good to
know that we're
saved by grace
to face.
That's important.
I mean it's
not a word.
It's not of
ourselves.
It's the
gift of God
and so we
can't take
credit.
It's important
to know but
unfortunately when
we end there
we don't end
with something
wrong but we
end with
something
insufficient.
It devolves
into an
individual salvation
as the end
goal rather
than a goal
moving toward a
bigger picture.
salvation is
about being
made part
part of
this
experience
whose fault
is to
destroy God.
God, did
God save you
because he
loves you?
Yes.
Did God save
you because he
wants you in
heaven?
Yes.
But folks,
God saves you
because he wants
to invite you
into his mission
which is
bigger than
just you
and I
being
in heaven.
What's
it?
It's
what is
now?
It's
to me
that's
for
you know
the
St.
Patrick
which we're
going to
celebrate
some times
to stay
soon and
just so you're
aware,
I feel most
of you know
but maybe
there's
some of
you're
going to
say
Patrick's
day is
not about
a guy
wearing
green
holding
a green
four-leaf
clover
drinking
green
deer.
Patrick
actually
was at
retirement
age.
By the way
I'm
preaching it
myself
now.
I really
want to
reach
him.
But he
was at
retirement
age
and he
had been
three minutes
as a child
and made
to be a
slave in
Ireland
and by
God's
divine
province
escaped
and near
the end
of his
life
he
had
become
a
priest
and he
called
to go
back
and he
went to
the church
and said
can I
go back
to the
missionary
and he
said
those guys
are
unredeemable
they're a bunch
of warring
tribes that run
at you naked
and scream
and they're
unredeemable
the question
they're
and they're
they let him
go
and it's
kind of like
you know
what bad
can he do
and
unfortunately
my library
is all
over the
country right
now
I have
some here
and I
couldn't
find the
book
so I'm
going
through
memories
but from
retirement
until the end
of his life
he and his
team
was able
to win
about 37
separate
unwinnable
tribes
to the gospel
of Jesus Christ
I'm not talking
about 37
churches
we're talking
about planting
multiple churches
in 37
different
roaring
tribes
of people
who were
unredeemable
according to
people
he did it
not by
following
the Roman
model
where we
present the
gospel
people believe
and then
make us
belong
but he
flipped that
model
on his
home
he went
with others
who were
as committed
as him
because the
only people
who go to
a place
like that
are people
who are
really
committed
to the
gospel
it's
kind of
like a
friend of
mine
in India
had won
over numerous
tribes
in Odessa
at that
time
it was
called
Orissa
India
and medieval
people who
literally
lived in
trees
didn't wear
clothes
in their
second place
and spontaneously
started wearing
clothes
and every
one of the
evangelists
he sent
out there
they knew
that they
were likely
to get
malaria
when they
went
and someone
an American
when he was
reporting
said well
if they knew
they were
going to get
malaria
why did
they go
I think
we had a
community
of people
who said
in kind
of our
context
who cares
about malaria
it's not
the gospel
and so they
went into
these places
and they
didn't present
the gospel
they lived
in
they were
a canvas
they were a
canvas
in a
season
nation
a season
war in
trains
and as
they
moved
at this
canvas
they
had this
radical
hospitality
they invited
people into
their community
to come
and you can
just belong
we love you
just the way
you are
we welcome
you
radical
hospitality
and as
these people
lived among
these committed
this canvas
of life
they said
man I
want to
be part
of that
canvas
and they
said I
think I
believe
this stuff
and so
the altar
call if you
will
was not
to believe
but to
connect
we welcome
you in
to the
kingdom of
God
for
thanks
to
time
for by
days
who
faith
have you
been
saved
not of
words
yourselves
but
similar
days
for
we
are
here
kings
you can
hear some
words
from
right
over
the
next
couple
months
you've
already
heard
them
several
times
from
the
island
while
I
was
gone
it's
a
concept
that
we're
a
kingdom
after
we
are
a
canvas
of
God
living
in
a
world
that
needs
to be
part
of
the
kingdom
where
a
friend
of mine
used
to
say
I'm
a
Christian
traveling
on
an
American
passport
you know
prior to
the
reformation
interaction
between
the
church
and the
state
world
army
and
the
reformers
said
no
we're
not
there
but
they
didn't
go
too
far
because
they
said
no
the
church
is
falling
and
the
state
is
falling
and
we
have
to
do
better
and
so
church
over
the
state
and
we're
going
to
christianize
the
state
and
that's
why
you
sound
at the
time
of the
reformation
it was
kind of like
Winchester
was during the
civil war
you have no
going to
civil war
Winchester
was part of
the south
and part of
the north
and went back
and forth
70 times
and
they
actually
did
the
same
thing
they
would
become
the
king
would
become
looser
and
they
were
all
looser
and
then
the
king
would
convert
to
catholicism
and
it
would
all
become
castles
and
then
convert
back
and
sometimes
in
the
same
day
don't
know
who
was
winning
the
battle
because
reformers
had
this
but
the
radical
reformers
said
we're
not
into
that
we're
part
of
a
world
that
is
not
that
canvas
God
wants
to
incorporate
into
his
canvas
the
founding
pastor
of
Grace
Community
years
ago
whatever
used
to
say
we
love
you
just
love
you
too
much
to
leave
you
there
and
I
think
if
that
was
although
I
didn't
hear
those
words
of
that
we
serve
for
a
kingdom
of
place
but
we
welcome
right
into
hospitality
coming
the
luggage
of
Jesus
and
that
when
you
find
what
you
do
it
we
invite
you
to
connect
we
invite
you
to
be
part
of
the
kingdom
of
Christ
we
invite
you
to
be
part
of
this
wonderful
information
okay
canvas
for
the
next
one
for
we
back
there
I
gave
you
a
quick
line
the
second
song
we
did
can you
put
the
words
up
there
really
quick
because I
noticed
this
folks
he
didn't
canvas
that's
kind
of
American
translation
for
I
his
canvas
no
for
we
there
is
this
collective
nature
for
what
he
wanted
longer
a
slave
to
fear
I
am
a
child
of
God
if
Paul
were
writing
this
in
one
to
nine
that'd
be
great
but
he's
going to
put it
in
verse
he's
going to
say
we
are
no
longer
slaves
to
fear
we
are
children
of
God
go to
the
next
one
okay
maybe
I'll
slide
go to
the
third
slide
turn
from
see
you
surround
who
with
the
thorns
in fact
by the
way
we are
the
thorns
next
one
delivering
from
my
enemies
and
all
my
really
next
one
I
need
to
hear
where
I'm
going
this
one
that
really
jumped
out
at
me
okay
so
my
mother's
ruined
your
chosen
me
I
can
take
that
one
love
is
called
my
enemy
been
born
again
your
blood
flows
through
we can
say
our
babies
next
one
of
these
talked
about
the
yeah
you
split
the
fees
so
who
can
walk
through
I
mean
is that
not a
story
read
folk
I
don't
know
I
missed
that
part
of
the
story
I
thought
it
was
the
nation
of
Israel
that
walked
through
right
is there
another
Bible
that I'm
missing
somewhere
now
I'm
not
criticizing
song
and
I'm
not
all
about
rewriting
people
do
artwork
they're
doing
amazing
artwork
but
do you
realize
how
individualistic
our
society
really
is
all
of our
frameworks
I took it
at home
with my
mom
on
Friday
and I
was talking
about my
birth
I didn't
realize it
but it
makes
sense
the doctor
and the
nurse
were in
the
breathing
room
but not
even my
dad
was
allowed
in there
there
was
no
coach
and now
today
we often
in some
ways
the
current
generation
is slowly
getting
better
we're getting
a little
more
collectivist
but when I
was born
I was born
with just
my mom
and the
medical
community
and when I
was born
they didn't
put me
on my
mom
they took
away
and did
what they
called
a car
or something
did a bunch
of
sex and
everything
to make
sure
I was
healthy
before I
got to
come
over
and then
when I
went
home
the goal
was to
get me
into my
own
crib
and then
get me
from my
own
crib
into my
own
room
and then
into my
own bed
and then
we celebrate
my first
steps
I mean
how many
fathers or
mothers have
you heard
lament because
they weren't
there for
their child's
first steps
because
independence
individualism
is so
important
to us
you go to
India
and you'll
find three
to four
kids in
one bed
and that
bed is
when mom
and dad's
bedroom
you go
to India
and literally
a child
often is not
put on the
floor until
they're about
one
they can't
and have
these
wraps that
they put
around the
child and
over their
back
and the
child is
part of
an us
in the
very
get-go
in the
very
beginning
of life
you know
my wife
couldn't wait
until she
decided to
eat on
his own
and I
gotta tell
you
she
started
it too
early
for my
gross
meter
and she
took a
plate of
spaghetti
with all
the sauce
and I
mean there
was spaghetti
more on
him than
in his
mouth
and I
just you
know
honey I
gotta go
my
gross
meter
has
overloaded
because we
value
independence
and I'm
not saying
independence
is wrong
but I am
saying it
becomes
filters
over which
we read
our
Scriptures
because there
are as
many
or more
collective
symbols
metaphors
for salvation
uniquely
as they are
individually
we're living
stones
but we're living
built into a
spherical house
we're not a
stone on a
hill
we're not even
a building
on a hill
we're a city
we're a body
we're
you know we
talk about
being priests
we're all
priests
we're a
priesthood
we're the
flock of
God
we're the
bride of
God
in fact
the rest
of Ephesians
when you get
to the end
of the second
half of
Ephesians
chapter 2
verses 19
to 22
there's four
separate
metaphors
about this
act that
God is
doing of
bringing us
to make
us his
people
and we're
all
collective
every one
of them
one more
illustration
and I'll
go to the
next word
and the
will
tell us
you know
that when
we start
to work
as a
logistics
of
merging
we use
a Christian
software
and the
lets us
keep a
kind of a
database
of who
people are
and their
coming
it allows
them to keep
chunk of
giving
so that we
can give
receipts
to people
with
services and
purposes
it allows
us to put
our songs
together
and let
anyone
get started
but I'm
going to
take a
whole lot
of stuff
planning
I think
that's what
it's called
I'm not
sure
I'm
technologically
illiterate
I mean
I'm a
technophobe
digital
expert
but
did you
know that
when we
went to
them and
we said
okay so
two churches
and we're
going to
merge
what is
the protocol
to merge
planning
things
they said
well
we have
protocols to
divide
but we'll
do not
have
a
protocol
for
two
congregations
to merge
that is
a
powerful
metaphor
it is
society
African
Pilistries
were invited
to
a conference
from all
of the
globe
invited
to a conference
here in the
U.S.
and they
decided to
bless the
African
Pilistries
and each
African
Pilistries
got their
own
room
these
were adults
were established
Pilistries
in fact
they were
established
enough
that they
were chosen
to be
thrown over
on the
organization
nickel
and go
through
this
conference
and said
we want
a blessing
to each
their own
room
by day
three
house
people
went to
the
conference
leaders
and they
said
we think
that
half
or more
of your
African
pastors
have all
except
death
and they're
like
what do
you know
you should
do
well
there's
no
soup
things
in the
room
the
cows
aren't
used
and they're
dead
have not
been
slept in
you know
they're at
the conference
they're not
in their
rooms
and they
went to
one of the
lead African
pastors
and said
what's going
on here
and he said
I've never
slept in
a room
by myself
and so
two
three
or four
pastors
all need
into one
ring
and said
for them
this we
is part
and parcel
of their
Christian
experience
for
we
for we
are
now
Ryan is
going to
really
have to
unpack
this one
in two
weeks
because
I'm going
to give
the fun
part
he's going
to give
the more
challenging
part
we are
means
it's a
done
deal
we are
his
canvas
it's a
done
deal
folks
it's not
saying
we should
be
it's not
saying
become
like
it's
not
grow
into
it's
we
are
so we
his
canvas
we
exist
as his
canvas
and
we're his
masterpiece
and this
is those
back to
my
earlier
comment
about
the
kingdom
is
here
and yet
not
it's
here
but
it's
not
we
are
his
canvas
and
it's
still
kind of
cool
in there
and why
do I talk
about the
we are
you'll see this
for me over
and over
in the
Scriptures
the
imperative
is based
on the
indicative
God
states
what
is
true
and
they
say
go
live
into
it
you
are
forgiven
live
like
it
you
are
holy
go
live
like
it
you
are
the
bride
of
Christ
you know
Jesus is
coming back
for a
bride
without
spot
or
wrinkle
so here
you must
just
throw
hands
but does
anyone
actually
think
it
means
he's
going to
wait
till you
get
back
together
because that's
the case
he ain't
never
coming
back
folks
i know
some of
you are
saying
no wait
wait
this is
the bride
without
spot
or
wrinkle
yep
and then
you're
saying
okay
this is
your first
sunday
here
isn't it
not
so it's
not hard
to look
around
and see
some spots
and some
wrinkles
but in
the economy
of God
we all
love
where is
masterpiece
candy
the purpose
of which
is to
display
Jesus
God
the
eudema
we are
a masterpiece
not to show
the masterpiece
but to show
the creator
of the masterpiece
we are
here
by the way
so English
doesn't always do
what sometimes
Greek can do
and I don't like
to refer to
Greek too often
but I just
can't talk
at a time
in this
passage
the word
his
actually
shows up
in the position
of cognizance
in other words
it is the
first word
in this
little section
of Scripture
it doesn't say
for we are
his
workmanship
or we are
his canvas
but it says
his
for we are
because Paul
wants to
emphasize
that we are
his
people
he is
doing this
you know
when I
so Ryan
left before
we did
the modes
and I'm sure
he was a little
nervous
what if they
blow it
but I trust
the people
I know
and I left
after we merge
and I had
the same
fears
but the reality
is
we're his
kids
and Paul
wants to
make that
very clear
sound
we are
his
kids
but this
one's
public
okay
takeaways
and then we
don't do
them to
community
folks as
we look
at our
letters
cannabis
is made
by the
grace
and it's
true
his work
his act
his doing
and it's
for his glory
he is going
to show
himself
to the world
he created
to his
canvas
that he
has created
and we're
it
by grace
and faith
but as a
canvas
we are
a separate
kingdom
we're a
outpost
the kingdom
is good
in this
local
congregation
this
local
congregation
just happens
to be
a manifestation
in the city
of Winchester
of his
wonderful
canvas
of his
glory
as his
brother
and so
we get
to be
an outpost
of that
kingdom
and it's
an outpost
where the end
result is a
done deal
God's
full kingdom
is coming
redemption
and fully
happy
he will
win
the universe
and we get
to be part
of that
and work
for an
outpost
in a place
where it
doesn't always
feel like that
just like
if you think
of the
American West
some of those
outposts
that we put
out there
you're never
going to make it
we're done
by grace
we're a kingdom
outpost
that is
called not
just to protect
but for right
to find
kingdom outpost
that says
we're welcome
all of you
we love you
just the way
you are
now we love you
too much
to leave you
because our
goal is that
you're included
into the
Kansas
and not
everything gets
to be in
the Kansas
it takes
grace by faith
but from our
place
you're welcome
and it's a
place at which
people say
now I think
I believe
this
and our
call
is to
commit
my biggest
fear when the
church grows
is the church
gets weak
that's my
biggest fear
and now
post that
Jesus
has called
us to do
my commitment
happens
not one that
shows up on
Sunday
just like
to have good
dinner in
Scotland
and I
couldn't like
it and that's
why I did
that's for those
who haven't yet
committed
because somehow
we're called to
do the
cannabis
to destroy
the world
and keep
the end result
of my salvation
is the glory
and my salvation
is a piece
part of it
I get to
participate
so I'm going
to invite you
to hear
and I'm just
going to
get a
fourth
station
bread
and
cup
there are
the individual
ones
that are
seeking
for 13
of those
I suspect
that by
our second
month
I'm going
to figure
out how
to direct
you
but
right now
I wouldn't
spirit of
God
direct
you
spirit of
God
did
take
care
of us
and make
orders
so
I hope
you'll be
ready
but I want
to remind
you as we
go to
partake
of communion
that the
life that Jesus
inaugurated
communion
was at the
moment that
as their
great role
model
he was
clearly going
all in
for his
father
all in
for the
kingdom
all in
for the
kingdom
that God
was creating
and building
that for
him
in that
moment
he was
not
inviting
to
believe
he was
inviting
to
command
he was
inviting
to a
radical
journey
kingdom
focused
we're
talking
to
communion
here
that means
if Jesus
is your
Lord and
Savior
you are
welcome
to
take
you
do not
have to
be
a member
here
you don't
have to
be a
regular
tender
here
but we
hope that
everyone
as you
partake
of
the
sacrifice
of
Jesus
if you
have the
same
mindset
that the
early
disciples
had
in those
three days
partaking
and then
walking
and
and realizing
the
common
union
that Jesus
was calling
them to
for the
moment
as
his
moment
Lord
Jesus
on the
night
that you
were betrayed
you did
take bread
and you
took it
you did
take a cup
and you
you renamed
it
you redefined
he told us
as often
as we
eat and
drink
this
bread
and this
cup
we do
so
in
remembrance
of
you
at that
moment
of
ultimate
communion
for us
and for
us
now
Lord
may we
experience
your
grace
both in
defeating
and in
going
as we
partake
of the
sacrifice
of Jesus
and celebrate
that we
are his
children
so